#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/thorstenduechting (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Analyst Relations Social Media Marketing

### Languages

Deutsch Englisch

# **Thorsten Duechting**

Head of Marketing & Communications Germany Frankfurt

## Summary

Thorsten Düchting positions Computacenter as a leading IT services provider and employer of choice in the market as well as internally to the employees. Furthermore he supports sales as well as recruiting activities of Computacenter with strategic and target group oriented marketing and communications activities.

Thorsten leads the Marketing & Communications team of Computacenter Germany. In this role he is responsible for the marketing and PR strategy and all integrated communications activities including PR, Marketing (incl. Content Marketing), Social Media, Web and partly Analyst Relations. Additionally he is responsible for central managed internal communications in Germany, specific international communication activities and campaigns of the Computacenter group.

Prior to joining Computacenter Thorsten worked for several communications agencies and advised customers like a global leading industry analyst house, the leading German provider of information and communications technology, a leading US telecommunications company, an IT consulting company, a Japanese mobile phone vendor as well as some software companies.

Thorsten completed his law studies at the University of Bonn and joined the certified training "Effective Managing & Performing" of Malik Management Zentrum St. Gallen as well as the Talent Program of Computacenter Germany.

## Experience

Computacenter
Head of Marketing & Communications Germany
July 2015 - Present (6 years 10 months)
Kerpen

Responsible for all integrated communications activities (PR, Marketing incl. Content Marketing, Social Media, Web and partly Analyst Relations) as well as for selected international communication campaigns. Additional responsible for central managed internal communications.

Computacenter AG & Co. oHG

6 years 2 months

Director Communications September 2013 - June 2015 (1 year 10 months) Kerpen

Responsible for all Marketing, PR, Social Media and Analyst Relations activities in Germany as well as for central managed internal communications.

Director Corporate Communications May 2009 - August 2013 (4 years 4 months) Kerpen

Responsible for all PR, Social Media and Analyst Relations activities in Germany as well as for central managed internal communications.

Computacenter AG & Co.oHG
Public & Analyst Relations Manager
November 2006 - April 2009 (2 years 6 months)
Kerpen

HFN Kommunikation GmbH Analyst & Public Relations Consultant May 2005 - October 2006 (1 year 6 months)

billo PR GmbH Public Relations Consultant February 2002 - April 2005 (3 years 3 months)

Oberlandesgericht Düsseldorf Rechtsreferanda (Trainee Solicitor) January 1999 - January 2002 (3 years 1 month)

Arbeitsamt Düsseldorf/Employment Office Sachbearbeiter June 1998 - December 1998 (7 months)

Engagement in the Election Campaign 1998
Page 2 of 3

Supporter April 1998 - May 1998 (2 months) Bonn

Deutscher Bundestag - Parliamentary Commissioner of the Armed Forces Sachbearbeiter October 1997 - March 1998 (6 months)

## Education

The University of Bonn Dipl-Jur., Law · (1991 - 1997)